Contact

+971543712358 (Mobile) rajaosama.me@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rajaosama (LinkedIn)

rajaosama.me/ (Portfolio) github.com/Raja0sama (Personal) supersami.medium.com/ (Blog)

Top Skills

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Redux.js

Electro

Languages

English (Professional Working)

Certifications

ACCP pro

JavaScript (Basic)

Rest API (Intermediate)

Problem Solving (Basic)

Honors-Awards

Android Developer 1st

Publications

Detect React Route Change in Vanilla JavaScript

Automatic Deployment with GitHub on Any Server Instance without GitHub workflow or SSH

Writing a Captcha Validator with Express

https://javascript.plainenglish.io/ write-a-simple-static-sitegenerator-to-convert-htmlhardcoded-values-and-to-dynamicvalues-8f59bb1d9d34

Injecting Javascript Inside Electron Webview

Raja Osama

Senior Software Engineer

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Summary

Hi, my name is Raja Osama and I am a highly skilled and versatile software developer with a strong passion for Javascript. With over five years of experience in the IT industry, I have developed a wide range of web and mobile applications for various startups and clients as a freelancer. I am a proactive and adaptable learner who is always eager to acquire new skills and techniques, both technical and cultural.

In addition to my professional pursuits, I am also a curious and adventurous individual who loves to travel and explore the world. My goal is to visit as many countries as possible, immersing myself in new cultures and experiences. I am also fascinated by the wonders of space and the cosmos, and hope to continue learning about these subjects in my spare time.

As a tech agnostic polyglot programmer, I am able to adapt to any environment and work with a variety of programming languages and frameworks. I am confident in my ability to deliver high-quality software solutions and am always looking for new challenges and opportunities to grow as a developer.

Experience

RAKBANK

Software Engineer February 2023 - Present (6 months)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Lead the pioneering integration of artificial intelligence (AI) technologies within RAKBANK.

including the implementation of semantic search, embedding techniques using ADA, and the

utilization of advanced language models such as GPT-4, GPT Turbo 3.5 for intent classification.

categorization, and other relevant applications.

Collaborate with cross-functional teams to identify and understand business requirements, translating them into technical solutions that leverage AI capabilities.

Architect and design scalable and efficient software systems, ensuring high performance, reliability, and security standards are met.

Work on multiple projects simultaneously, showcasing versatility as a polyglot engineer proficient in various programming languages and frameworks such as Java, Node.js, Python, React,

Develop and maintain full-stack applications, encompassing both front-end and back-end

components, with a focus on delivering exceptional user experiences and seamless

integration with existing systems.

React Native, and Spring Boot.

Albatha Next Sr. Full Stack Engineer April 2022 - February 2023 (11 months) Dubai, United Arab Emirates

As a Full-Stack Senior Software Engineer at Albatha Next, I have been responsible for designing, developing, and optimizing the front-end application scaffolding on Next JS using a future-proof project structure and pre-commit setups such as Husky, EsLint, Jest, and TS Checks to ensure code quality. I have also developed and deployed applications built on React JS, Next JS, and SpringBoot.

In collaboration with the Medical and Automotive teams, I have worked to build the best and most reliable applications for these market segments, focusing on all of the company's main product lines. I have been involved in the entire software development lifecycle, from gathering requirements to release.

I have also worked to bring about change in the business by introducing the use of modern development tools such as Next JS and Tailwind CLI.

Through my work, I have added SpringBoot and event-driven architecture and microservices to my skill set, enabling me to build scalable applications.

Atompoint

Sr. Full Stack Engineer March 2020 - April 2022 (2 years 2 months)

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

As a Sr. Full Stack Engineer at ATOMPOINT, a consultancy company that helps businesses create and launch products, I have developed, tested, and deployed 15+ applications and websites on various frameworks. I have also demonstrated strong ability in architecting infrastructures, backends, and frontends for performant and streamlined development, as demonstrated by creating an Uber-like water delivery mobile app based on GCP, NodeJS, and React Native.

In addition to my technical skills, I have also collaborated effectively on all stages of the software development lifecycle, from requirement gathering to production releases. I have developed a webinar platform from scratch, including ideation, design, and development, and have experience in converting static sites to dynamic web applications using 11ty, contentful, and nodeJS. Overall, I am a highly skilled and experienced full stack engineer with a track record of delivering successful projects.

DFM

Full stack Software Developer March 2017 - March 2020 (3 years 1 month)

Karāchi, Sindh, Pakistan

As a Full-Stack Senior Software Engineer at Dawood Fiber Mills, a parent company that owns multiple businesses in Karachi and Dubai, including superstores, I served as a technical lead with a successful track record in managing and resolving software-related issues. I demonstrated strong ability in developing 10+ in-house applications on various frameworks, and was skilled in creating mobile applications for Android and iOS, storefronts, and desktop applications, as well as integrating them with existing systems. I also provided extended support for the company's existing systems, including those of its sub-company, Dominion Stores.

Education

Middlesex University Dubai

Bachelor of Science - BS, Information Technology · (September 2021 - April 2022)

Aptech Pakistan

Advance Diploma In Software Engineering, Computer Software Engineering · (August 2017 - February 2020)

Newports Institute of Communications and Economics
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (February 2019 - March 2020)